<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on GameDev</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thoughts on GameDev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Update</title>
      <link>/posts/2020/10/update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020/10/update/</guid>
      <description>Quite a bit has changed as we move towards alpha. This post will mostly deal with environmental rendering changes. Basically, all the prototypes are being generalized and systems are being merged and replaced for the best trade offs. This also means Low/Med/High graphics quality levels are being roughed out. All images here are from a GTX 1080 Ti running on Ubuntu 20.04 at 2K vsynced to 60Hz. Once I get an RTX card I will add an Ultra mode focused on hardware based ray tracing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>/posts/2020/03/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020/03/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Testing out using hugo for blogging. I was going to bring over some old blog posts to here, but decided it might be better to update those posts and roll them out later.
Today I&amp;rsquo;ll just link to the video of the transient material instance (MI) system that was put in not long ago. This system allows every object to have it&amp;rsquo;s own procedurally generated MI to handle various parameters of VFX materials such as volume, colors, patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Blog about game engine development, art, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weapon Models Update</title>
      <link>/posts/2020/02/weapon-models-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020/02/weapon-models-update/</guid>
      <description>Some renders of a couple of the weapons that got banged out in between coding sessions last week in case you missed it:
#screenshotsaturday #indiegames
        Weapons modeled in blender with material in Substance &amp;nbsp;  My hard surface/box modeling skills are OKish enough to throw out/replace all the older models now I think. Expect many geometry/material updates before alpha starting with various props.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WIP Character Creator</title>
      <link>/posts/2020/02/wip-character-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020/02/wip-character-creator/</guid>
      <description>WIP Character Creator/Appearance system for my engine/game. You can adjust skin tone/paint colors, -/+ various body parts and sizes. The video is of my favorite player race, but there are others. 100% developed and ran in Linux. ;)
#indiedev #indiegames #screenshotsaturday
 Variation Video From Tweet &amp;nbsp;
 Character Create UI is currently done in imgui for faster development. Will have a pretty user UI later, but this let&amp;rsquo;s me and modders edit the UI while the game is running to prototype much faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WIP Moon Phase / Tides</title>
      <link>/posts/2020/02/wip-moon-phase-/-tides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020/02/wip-moon-phase-/-tides/</guid>
      <description>Moon Phase Feb 4, 2020 I don&amp;rsquo;t think I showed working moon phase yet?
The stars are all done in a screenspace shader, and the moon is just doing a simple alpha blend based on vector driven by day of the month w/o additional occlusion as yet. Lunar cycle isn&amp;rsquo;t completely modeled yet. An average night the moon should shift ~12-15 degrees.
  Tides Jan 11, 2020 Shows how time affects tides visually and with physics feedback for specific islands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Night Sky Test</title>
      <link>/posts/2019/10/basic-night-sky-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019/10/basic-night-sky-test/</guid>
      <description>Late entry for #screenshotsaturday really basic flickering stars that may not show up on video lol. I&amp;rsquo;m looking into using an actual star map to navigate by in game later on&amp;hellip; This is more of a mood test while a had a couple of hours.
  Maybe you can see them in images:
           Screenshot Gallery &amp;nbsp;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sailing to the lighthouse</title>
      <link>/posts/2019/09/sailing-to-the-lighthouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019/09/sailing-to-the-lighthouse/</guid>
      <description>Stupid lighthouse&amp;hellip; I wonder why they have the beacon lit during the daytime? Why does it have 10 floors? #screenshotsaturday #indiedev #linux
 Old sailing video last seen on twitter &amp;nbsp;
 Rough pass done for lighthouse with physics and basic materials. Every floor is about as tall as the &amp;ldquo;cog&amp;rdquo; ship. Made some modular spiral staircases to remove them later because no one likes spinning around and around while running at walls&amp;hellip; go figure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procedural Terrain Material</title>
      <link>/posts/2019/09/procedural-terrain-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019/09/procedural-terrain-material/</guid>
      <description>Late entry for #screenshotsaturday
I was taking a break from some other work, and reworked terrain shader proc sand to do all this with one texture and some slope/elevation aware noise and warping with LoD (no blending):
 Video of procedural material at shoreline &amp;nbsp;
 Here&amp;rsquo;s a still. Also did some &amp;lsquo;swirly noise&amp;rsquo; for blending grass/dirt types over terrain (camera very far away to see the effect) that looks like erosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WIP RPG with sailing, procedural worlds, and mod support</title>
      <link>/posts/2019/08/wip-rpg-with-sailing-procedural-worlds-and-mod-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019/08/wip-rpg-with-sailing-procedural-worlds-and-mod-support/</guid>
      <description>This page has some tweets + imgur posts combined here related to first posts of WIP RPG. These were some of the media tests done for social media video uploads. Using these to test video via hugo now.
WIP RPG showing scale of a &amp;ldquo;small&amp;rdquo; 8x8 island. SDF proxy shadows and other &amp;ldquo;far&amp;rdquo; LoDs only for now. I had to crop out 1080p from the 2k image to record for now, sorry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting Model Tweet</title>
      <link>/posts/2019/06/lighting-model-tweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019/06/lighting-model-tweet/</guid>
      <description>Back to my take on OrenNayar/Beckmann (needs better energy conservation) Player Hus generation from floor plans (line art,multi-floor) New attachment system replaces all use of old one No work on hybrid shadows yet  #screenshotsaturday
Yeah, the mage with horns is using the Burley with GGX I tried for a bit and tossed. I like the highlights of my old 2-pass better but needs work to avoid getting too hot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screenshot Saturday, Side Eye</title>
      <link>/posts/2019/06/screenshot-saturday-side-eye/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019/06/screenshot-saturday-side-eye/</guid>
      <description>Hey guys, let me do the talking &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m sure this shop keeper will want to covert. Nothing like last time.
   side eye   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terrain and Breadknives</title>
      <link>/posts/2019/05/terrain-and-breadknives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019/05/terrain-and-breadknives/</guid>
      <description>What kind of knives do you guys use for slicing your procedural voxel terrain? When I slice with a serrated bread knife I get all these little blocks on the edges.
(Above is a joke.)
Terrain generated with only 3 density functions clipped at 4x4 sectors. #screenshotsaturday
OK, one more shitpost while taking a sick day.
#screenshotsaturday
        Screenshot Gallery &amp;nbsp;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noise!</title>
      <link>/posts/2016/01/noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016/01/noise/</guid>
      <description>Update Screenshots with realistic sized trees on same terrain, and fixed some links. :3
        Tree scale now in 10-20m range &amp;nbsp;  I noticed r/proceduralgeneration has a lot activity lately, so I thought I would do quick post on how I&amp;rsquo;m generating my current test islands with only 4 functions. This is what they typically look like:
   Terrain generated by simple density functions   Terrian Geometry I basically use both 2d and 3d simplex noise to add and subtract a global density function, which is described per terrain cube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screenshot Weekend</title>
      <link>/posts/2015/12/screenshot-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015/12/screenshot-weekend/</guid>
      <description>Well, mostly focused on non-renderer stuff this weekend like bringing more of the web editor interface into in-game viewport UI. A few minor improvements to sky with a simple per fragment Preetham, and ported all my shaders to the updated Kagura shader lang to get ready for Vulkan.
              Same scene with different foliage seeds and lighting &amp;nbsp;  Below is a simple test for tiling fbm independently for foliage generation with the threaded voxel sectors, so there is no need to do another physics based ray cast pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ugly Terrain</title>
      <link>/posts/2014/07/ugly-terrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014/07/ugly-terrain/</guid>
      <description>Getting tired of pure voxel terrain again, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to move voxel system to more of a detail terrain painting system. GPU Clipmaps are cool again, and much more flexible when it comes to foliage deco &amp;ndash; so hopefully this will be the last ugly terrain screenshot. Making the system to generate foliage with raycasts as seen in ye old island demo as fun for programmer art, however for deco painting artists don&amp;rsquo;t like that kind of thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrer vers Hugo depuis Jekyll</title>
      <link>/migrer-vers-hugo-depuis-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/migrer-vers-hugo-depuis-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;déplacez-le-contenu-statique-vers-static&#34;&gt;Déplacez le contenu statique vers &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll a une règle comme quoi tout répertoire qui ne commence pas par &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; sera
copié tel-quel dans le répertoire &lt;code&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt;. Hugo garde tout le contenu statique
dans le répertoire &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;. Vous devez donc déplacer tout ce type de contenu
là-dedans. Avec Jekylll, l&amp;rsquo;arborescence ressemblant à ceci :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/
    ▾ images/
        logo.png
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terrain and Biomes and Flora oh my</title>
      <link>/posts/2013/10/terrain-and-biomes-and-flora-oh-my/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013/10/terrain-and-biomes-and-flora-oh-my/</guid>
      <description>So I dusted off the terrain / biome system to hook it up to the voxel terrain system, since it makes a lot more sense to model very large landmasses in a way people can understand. Density functions by parts isn&amp;rsquo;t a bad thing, but even if you expose this with a UI flow graph &amp;ndash; who the fuck is going to understand it that also wants to use a flow graph chart?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voxel Terrain Sector Preview</title>
      <link>/posts/2013/09/voxel-terrain-sector-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013/09/voxel-terrain-sector-preview/</guid>
      <description>Got the basic voxel terrain in today. The most time was spent on new ways to generate and enqueue Voxels, RenderMesh, PhysicsMesh in various worker threads and sync them amongst all the subsystems. Also refactored some of the math library and noise generation while in there to avoid overlap.
   Voxel Terrain Sectors 2x1x2   The scale of this image required me to adjust my camera&amp;hellip; typical player could be about as big as a pixel here&amp;hellip; going to hook this up to my biome and erosion simulation next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isosurface Extraction done quick</title>
      <link>/posts/2013/09/isosurface-extraction-done-quick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013/09/isosurface-extraction-done-quick/</guid>
      <description>Cross post from Google+:
Voxels and Triplanar Mapping only took a day and a half thanks to the excellent docs from Nvidia and my awesome little engine that could. Going to work in real-time editing and maybe tessellation guided by isosurface extraction later if I don&amp;rsquo;t get sidetracked with other big features. This is a CPU converted isosurface to standard mesh to use the CPU side physics. eg voxels -&amp;gt; mesh.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>